# STEPHANIE QUICK

Chicago, IL 60656

(708) 218-1601 - stephaniequick1997@gmail.com

•	_			
	1	T	T/	9
	1	1	ĸ	

Resume: https://snqportfolio.netlify.app/

Github: https://github.com/snquick

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/stephanie-quick-55b015212/

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Motivated developer to contribute to team success through hard work, problem solving, and excellent critical thinking skills. Clear understanding of programming languages, such as HTML/CSS, C#, C, JavaScript, and Java. Experienced in using GitHub for software projects; Firebase, React.Js, and Microsoft Azure applications to deploy Web Apps and SQL servers. Participated in using the Agile methodology through project phases with the usage of sprints, scrum teams, epics, and story points.

## TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE & EXPERTISE

**Operating Systems:** Windows, MacOSX, Unix, Linux **Programming Languages:** C#, C, Java, Visual Basic

Web: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, React.JS, WordPress, Bootstrap

Database Management: MySQL, Oracle SQL, Firebase

Applications: PuTTY, VirtualBox, Microsoft Office, Google Suite, Microsoft Teams, Slack, AWS,

Microsoft Azure

**IDEs**: Eclipse, Visual Studio Code, Android Studio, IntelliJ IDEA

**Development Tools**: Unity, Git, Jira, Trello

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## 02/2023 to Current Application Developer I

**Southern Company** – Atlanta, Georgia (Remote)

- Assigned as supporting developer on deployed applications for continuing development support, such as resolving errors and client issues using ticketing system
- Actively primary developer for work management applications that utilize Java, C#, and SQL databases
- Assist in identifying potential solutions that leverage (when COTS system) rather than customization.
- Modify existing software to correct errors, to adapt it to new hardware, or to upgrade interfaces and improve performance based on specifications, with supervision.
- Able to troubleshoot, debug, maintain and improve existing software with supervision.

## **Lewis University Department Of Computer Science**

- Write weekly articles for Flyer Tech department blog
- Help tutor and grade for professors
- Classes include Software Engineering, Object-Oriented Programming, Programming Languages, Introduction to Computer Science, Algorithms and Data Structures, and Web Distributed Programming
- Assist with student clubs such as ACM-W Chapter and Girls Create with Technology

#### 05/2020 to 08/2020 Software Developer Intern

## **Carry The One Counseling**

- Developed multi-platform mobile game into alpha, using Unity and C#
- Used Agile methodology throughout duration of development process
- Analyzed source code to identify and rectify potential functionality issues
- Wrote all technical documentation for new software in development.

## 02/2017 to 03/2020 IT Media Support Intern

## **Lewis University**

- Increased customer satisfaction and repeat business through relentless pursuit of resolutions to problems arising with classroom equipment, protecting company reputation and loyal client base
- Troubleshoot all computer issues professors or clients were having on-site, and relentlessly resolved problems within short periods of time
- Primarily used Web Help Desk ticketing system to view and create tickets, as well as communicate with higher administration and coworkers
- Assisted with on-campus events to ensure clients were satisfied with their technology and if any
  problems occurred, they would be resolved quickly and efficiently
- Documented all unresolved issues to notify higher administration

#### **EDUCATION**

05/2022 Master of Science: Computer Science

Lewis University - Romeoville, IL

GPA: 3.9/4.0

• Concentration in Software Engineering

05/2020 Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

Lewis University - Romeoville, IL

GPA: 3.4/4.0

- Concentration in Pervasive Computing and Cyber Security Operations
- Study Abroad Experience: Edge Hill University, Ormskirk, England, UK [Spring 2019]
- Dean's List [Fall 2019, Spring 2020]
- Recipient, Lewis University Deans Scholarship